

Dhruvakumar Jonnagaddala

 Paracknell, England
 ■ erion225@gmail.com
 □ 07440278065
 ■ https://dhruvakumar-jonnagaddala.github.io/

SUMMARY

DevOps / Cloud Platform Engineer with 11+ years of experience, equipped with a fair knowledge of a repertoire of technologies used by the Waitrose (top retailer of UK), Servana Managed Services (Official Cloudbees Partners for EMEA) & Target (US second largest retailer).

EXPERIENCE

Sr DevOps / Cloud Platform Engineer | Waitrose and Partners | Bracknell, United Kingdom | August 2019 - Present

- Led efforts to transition legacy infrastructure to the cloud, built a self service portal for provisioning and de-provisioning of resources, ensuring automation and resilience of the solution.
- $\cdot \, \text{Managed, provisioned and configured cloud platforms and services as Amazon AWS and Google Cloud Platform for various business units majorly } \\ \text{E-commerce.}$
- · Managed day-to-day operations of the AWS environment and other cloud platforms including, but not limited to, deploying and maintaining applications and server infrastructure, user management and access control, Log Aggregation using Elastic Stack(ELK) and performance monitoring.
- Instrumented over 150+ micro services and developed automated monitoring and solutions for Microservices and underlying infrastructure components powered by popular tools (cloud watch, grafana, prometheus, pagerduty on call integration).
- Infrastructure as code Cloud infrastructure provisioning via Cloudformation and Terraform. Configuration as code Config management using ansible. Develop and maintain custom ansible modules and plugins.
- Provision and manage highly available Kubernetes clusters. Enable cluster security tools, release management and microservice deployments powered by helm.
- · CI/CD Design, build and maintain continues integration and deployment pipelines (powered by Groovy DSL). Blue/Green/Canary deployments. Building quality checks for the delivery team to apply early to the code pipeline.
- · DevOps tools(Jenkins, Nexus, Sonarqube, Contrast, Keyclock, Elastic Stack, etc.,) installation/life cycle management.
- · Creating cost optimisation metrics to monitor, optimise the total spend on cloud resources and support cost effective resources.
- · Experience with container-based deployments using Docker, working with Docker images and Docker registries.

DevOps / Cloud Platform Engineer | Servana Managed Services | Bournemouth, United Kingdom | September 2018 - August 2019

- · Built end to end procurement and management of popular DevOps tools on Kubernetes hosting within span of 6 months.
- · 99.99% Managed Services Platform availability for the customers.
- · Build and maintain CI/CD for Mobile Applications. Enabled migrations from Bitrise to Jenkins within a month.
- · Highly scalable infrastructure with inbuilt security SSL, WAF, Brute force detection, data encryption in transit and at rest.
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$ Minimal downtime tool upgrades with less than a minute.
- · Updates and upgrades to the platform driven through GitOps.

DevOps Engineer | JCPenney | Bangalore, India | February 2018 - September 2018

- · Configuration management automation of WebLogic, WebSphere & Linux upgrades using ansible.
- · Netcool to Splunk migration & automation.
- $\cdot \, \text{NetScaler Big-IP certs renewal leveraging Python} \, \& \, \text{Selenium API's}.$
- · Jira Administration user & license management automation leveraging Python & Jira's RestAPI.

DevOps Engineer | Tata Consultancy Services | Chennai, Uruguay, Bangalore | April 2010 - January 2018

- Enabled self-service tool for the developers and testers which procures the environments and notifies user via different channels (Email, Hipchat, Service now).
- $\cdot \text{ Overall environment build time reduced from 3 months to 1 hour. Infrastructure automation achieved with OpenStack Heat Orchestration API's followed by application installs via Configuration management tool Chef.}$
- · 99.99% Environment stability enabled via Elastic load balancers and Infra monitoring via Sensu.
- · Automation of manual steps using scripting languages (Bash, Shell PowerShell for windows).
- · Prepare weekly project status reports, risk mitigation plans, sent timely appropriate communications for escalations.
- · Set goals to team members, conducted monthly performance review and half yearly evaluation; attended project auditing for TCS.
- 140 Environments migrated from physical infrastructure to cloud in a span of 4 months.
- · Mitigated all challenges encountered with open source tools and with windows OS on cloud.
- · Acted as a Release coordinator for Manhattan product WMOS Manhattan 2013, UNIX AIX 7.1, Oracle 11G migration for top retailer.

EDUCATION

CERTIFICATIONS

Terraform Associate | Hashicorp | 2021

Earners of the HashiCorp Certified: Terraform Associate certification know the basic concepts, skills, and use cases associated with open source HashiCorp Terraform. They understand and can utilize Terraform according to the certification objectives. Additionally, they understand why enterprises choose to extend Terraform Open Source with Terraform Enterprise to solve business critical objectives. Earners of the HashiCorp Certified: Terraform Associate certification know the basic concepts, skills, and use cases associated with open source HashiCorp Terraform. They understand and can utilize Terraform according to the certification objectives. Additionally, they understand why enterprises choose to extend Terraform Open Source with Terraform Enterprise to solve business critical objectives.

Cloudbees Jenkins Engineer | Cloudbees | 2018

Certified CloudBees Jenkins Engineer (for proficiency with Jenkins and CloudBees Core)

SKILLS

AWS: EC2, Autoscaling, VPC, ECS, ECR, Lambda, S3, RDS, IAM, Elasticache, Kinesis, DynamoDB, CloudWatch, CloudFormation, CloudFront, API Gateway, EMR, CodePipeline, CodeDeploy, CodeBuild

Languages: Python, Java, Groovy, Bash, SQL

Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MSSQL, AWS Aurora, DynamoDB, Redis

Automation Tools: Jenkins, Gradle, Maven, Docker, Sonarqube, Contrast, Blackduck, Clair and more

Infrastructure-as-Code: Terraform, Cloudformation

Monitoring Tools: Grafana, Prometheus, InfluxDB, Splunk, Pingdom, New Relic

Templating: Jinja2, Helm

Configuration-as-code: Ansible

Container Orchestration: ECS, Docker Swarm, Kubernetes